<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Human electrophysiology | Open Neuroscience</title>
    <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/categories/human-electrophysiology/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://open-neuroscience.com/en/categories/human-electrophysiology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Human electrophysiology</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC BY SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://open-neuroscience.com/media/openneuroscience_logo_dark.svg</url>
      <title>Human electrophysiology</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/categories/human-electrophysiology/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>EmotiBit</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/emotibit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/emotibit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EmotiBit is a wearable sensor to capture high-quality emotional, physiological, and movement data from just about anywhere on the body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sean Montgomery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.emotibit.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.emotibit.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-video&#34;&gt;Project Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jbcL2jzyWj4&amp;amp;ab_channel=EmotiBit&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jbcL2jzyWj4&amp;amp;ab_channel=EmotiBit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Sean Montgomery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INCF NeuroStars</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/incf_neurostars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/incf_neurostars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Neurostars is an open source question and answer site that serves the INCF network and the global neuroscience community as a forum for knowledge exchange between neuroscience researchers at all levels of expertise, software developers, and infrastructure providers. Access to Neurostars is free to the neuroscience community thanks to the generous support of our sponsors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neurostars is a forum for research questions, software, infrastructure, scientific societies, and virtual courses, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software developers and infrastructure providers in need of a mechanism in which to engage and provide support to user communities and those in need of a platform to integrate tutorials and discussion forums (via INCF TrainingSpace)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scientific societies in need of a forum for knowledge exchange and support between members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtual course organizers in need of an archivable Q &amp;amp; A forum to support learning in their courses where access can be restricted to registered participants with automated notifications and the ability to have multiple, linked subdiscussion groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individuals in need of sharing ideas, asking questions and finding answers, and helping others within neuroscience without any cost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INCF team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://neurostars.org&#34;&gt;https://neurostars.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-video&#34;&gt;Project Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=veVD1olyaW4&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=veVD1olyaW4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Malin Sandström&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INCF Portal</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/incf_portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/incf_portal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The INCF portal is the guide to the INCF activities and its community resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INCF advances data reuse and reproducibility in brain research by coordinating the development of Open, FAIR, and Citable tools and resources for neuroscience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global INCF network&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;supports the development of neuroinformatics as a discipline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;moves neuroscience towards FORCE (a FAIR, Open, Research-object based, Citable Ecosystem)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;provides coordination of global neuroscience infrastructure through the development and endorsement of consensus-based standards and best practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;trains scientists, administrators, and students in using neuroinformatics tools and methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INCF provides materials, expertise, training, and standards and best practices for: 1) scientists seeking to improve their science through neuroinformatics, 2) infrastructure providers so they can do their jobs better and participate in the global network, and 3) those seeking to add their tools, services, and expertise to the INCF network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INCF currently has Governing and Associate Nodes spanning 4 continents, with an extended network comprising organizations, individual researchers, industry, and publishers. The INCF Secretariat supports the Nodes with outreach, project management, and administration of community-driven projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can join the INCF network: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.incf.org/join-incf&#34;&gt;https://www.incf.org/join-incf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INCF team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.incf.org&#34;&gt;https://www.incf.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-video&#34;&gt;Project Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=teFJ_W6nVUY&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=teFJ_W6nVUY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Malin Sandström&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MNE-Python</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/mne-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/mne-python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MNE is a software package for processing electrophysiological signals primarily from magnetoencephalographic (MEG) and electroencephalographic (EEG) recordings, and more recently sEEG, ECoG and fNIRS. It provides a comprehensive solution for data preprocessing, forward modeling (with boundary element models), distributed source imaging, time–frequency analysis, non-parametric multivariate statistics, multivariate pattern analysis, and connectivity estimation. Importantly, this package allows all of these analyses to be applied in both sensor or source space. MNE is developed by an international team, with particular care for computational efficiency, code quality, and readability, as well as the common goal of facilitating reproducibility in neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexandre Gramfort;Eric Larson;Denis Engemann;Daniel Strohmeier;Christian Brodbeck;Roman Goj;Mainak Jas;Teon Brooks;Lauri Parkkonen;Matti Hämäläinen;Jaakko Leppakangas;Jona Sassenhagen;Jean-Rémi King;Daniel McCloy;Marijn van Vliet;Clemens Brunner;Chris Holdgraf;Martin Luessi;Joan Massich;Guillaume Favelier;Andrew R. Dykstra;Mikolaj Magnuski;Stefan Appelhoff;Britta Westner;Richard Höchenberger;Robert Luke;Luke Bloy;Thomas Hartmann;Olaf Hauk;Adam Li&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mne.tools&#34;&gt;https://mne.tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SpikeInterface</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/spikeinterface/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/spikeinterface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SpikeInterface is a unified Python framework for spike sorting. With its high-level API, it is designed to be accessible and easy to use, allowing users to build full analysis pipelines for spike sorting (reading-writing (IO) / preprocessing / spike sorting / postprocessing / validation / curation / comparison / visualization) with a few lines of code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alessio Buccino*; Cole Hurwitz*; Samuel Garcia; Jeremy Magland; Josh Siegle; Matthias Hennig&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SpikeInterface/spikeinterface&#34;&gt;https://github.com/SpikeInterface/spikeinterface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-video&#34;&gt;Project Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nWJGwFB7oII&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nWJGwFB7oII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Alessio Buccino&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heuristic Spike Sorting Tuner (HSST), a framework to determine optimal parameter selection for a generic spike sorting algorithm</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/heuristic_spike_sorting_tuner_hsst_a_framework_to_determine_optimal_parameter_selection_for_a_generic_spike_sorting_algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/heuristic_spike_sorting_tuner_hsst_a_framework_to_determine_optimal_parameter_selection_for_a_generic_spike_sorting_algorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Extracellular microelectrodes frequently record neural activity from more than one neuron in the vicinity of the electrode. The process of labeling each recorded spike waveform with the identity of its source neuron is called spike sorting and is often approached from an abstracted statistical perspective. However, these approaches do not consider neurophysiological realities and may ignore important features that could improve the accuracy of these methods. Further, standard algorithms typically require selection of at least one free parameter, which can have significant effects on the quality of the output. We describe a Heuristic Spike Sorting Tuner (HSST) that determines the optimal choice of the free parameters for a given spike sorting algorithm based on the neurophysiological qualification of unit isolation and signal discrimination. A set of heuristic metrics are used to score the output of a spike sorting algorithm over a range of free parameters resulting in optimal sorting quality. We demonstrate that these metrics can be used to tune parameters in several spike sorting algorithms. The HSST algorithm shows robustness to variations in signal to noise ratio, number and relative size of units per channel. Moreover, the HSST algorithm is computationally efficient, operates unsupervised, and is parallelizable for batch processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David A. Bjanes; Lee B. Fisher; Robert A. Gaunt; Douglas J. Weber&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/davidbjanes/hsst&#34;&gt;https://github.com/davidbjanes/hsst&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
David Bjanes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
