<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Human electrophysiology | Open Neuroscience</title>
    <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/categories/human-electrophysiology/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://open-neuroscience.com/en/categories/human-electrophysiology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Human electrophysiology</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC BY SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://open-neuroscience.com/images/icon_hu98f7bdece981985d79e430785ac9bc37_26395_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Human electrophysiology</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/categories/human-electrophysiology/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>MNE-Python</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/mne-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/mne-python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MNE is a software package for processing electrophysiological signals primarily from magnetoencephalographic (MEG) and electroencephalographic (EEG) recordings, and more recently sEEG, ECoG and fNIRS. It provides a comprehensive solution for data preprocessing, forward modeling (with boundary element models), distributed source imaging, time–frequency analysis, non-parametric multivariate statistics, multivariate pattern analysis, and connectivity estimation. Importantly, this package allows all of these analyses to be applied in both sensor or source space. MNE is developed by an international team, with particular care for computational efficiency, code quality, and readability, as well as the common goal of facilitating reproducibility in neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexandre Gramfort;Eric Larson;Denis Engemann;Daniel Strohmeier;Christian Brodbeck;Roman Goj;Mainak Jas;Teon Brooks;Lauri Parkkonen;Matti Hämäläinen;Jaakko Leppakangas;Jona Sassenhagen;Jean-Rémi King;Daniel McCloy;Marijn van Vliet;Clemens Brunner;Chris Holdgraf;Martin Luessi;Joan Massich;Guillaume Favelier;Andrew R. Dykstra;Mikolaj Magnuski;Stefan Appelhoff;Britta Westner;Richard Höchenberger;Robert Luke;Luke Bloy;Thomas Hartmann;Olaf Hauk;Adam Li&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mne.tools&#34;&gt;https://mne.tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SpikeInterface</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/spikeinterface/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/spikeinterface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SpikeInterface is a unified Python framework for spike sorting. With its high-level API, it is designed to be accessible and easy to use, allowing users to build full analysis pipelines for spike sorting (reading-writing (IO) / preprocessing / spike sorting / postprocessing / validation / curation / comparison / visualization) with a few lines of code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alessio Buccino*; Cole Hurwitz*; Samuel Garcia; Jeremy Magland; Josh Siegle; Matthias Hennig&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SpikeInterface/spikeinterface&#34;&gt;https://github.com/SpikeInterface/spikeinterface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-video&#34;&gt;Project Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nWJGwFB7oII&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nWJGwFB7oII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Alessio Buccino&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heuristic Spike Sorting Tuner (HSST), a framework to determine optimal parameter selection for a generic spike sorting algorithm</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/heuristic_spike_sorting_tuner_hsst_a_framework_to_determine_optimal_parameter_selection_for_a_generic_spike_sorting_algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/heuristic_spike_sorting_tuner_hsst_a_framework_to_determine_optimal_parameter_selection_for_a_generic_spike_sorting_algorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Extracellular microelectrodes frequently record neural activity from more than one neuron in the vicinity of the electrode. The process of labeling each recorded spike waveform with the identity of its source neuron is called spike sorting and is often approached from an abstracted statistical perspective. However, these approaches do not consider neurophysiological realities and may ignore important features that could improve the accuracy of these methods. Further, standard algorithms typically require selection of at least one free parameter, which can have significant effects on the quality of the output. We describe a Heuristic Spike Sorting Tuner (HSST) that determines the optimal choice of the free parameters for a given spike sorting algorithm based on the neurophysiological qualification of unit isolation and signal discrimination. A set of heuristic metrics are used to score the output of a spike sorting algorithm over a range of free parameters resulting in optimal sorting quality. We demonstrate that these metrics can be used to tune parameters in several spike sorting algorithms. The HSST algorithm shows robustness to variations in signal to noise ratio, number and relative size of units per channel. Moreover, the HSST algorithm is computationally efficient, operates unsupervised, and is parallelizable for batch processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David A. Bjanes; Lee B. Fisher; Robert A. Gaunt; Douglas J. Weber&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/davidbjanes/hsst&#34;&gt;https://github.com/davidbjanes/hsst&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
David Bjanes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
