<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computational Neuroscience | Open Neuroscience</title>
    <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/categories/computational-neuroscience/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://open-neuroscience.com/categories/computational-neuroscience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Computational Neuroscience</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC BY SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://open-neuroscience.com/media/openneuroscience_logo_dark.svg</url>
      <title>Computational Neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/categories/computational-neuroscience/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>BigPint Bioconductor package that makes BIG (RNA-seq) data pint-sized</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/bigpint_bioconductor_package_that_makes_big__rna_seq__data_pint_sized/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/bigpint_bioconductor_package_that_makes_big__rna_seq__data_pint_sized/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The BigPint package can help examine any large multivariate dataset. However, we note that the example datasets and example code in this package consider RNA-sequencing datasets. If you are using this software for RNA-sequencing data, then it can help you confirm that the variability between your treatment groups is larger than that between your replicates and determine how various normalization techniques in popular RNA-sequencing analysis packages (such as edgeR, DESeq2, and limma) affect your dataset. Moreover, you can easily superimpose lists of differentially expressed genes (DEGs) onto your dataset to check that they show the expected patterns (large variability between treatment groups and small variability between replicates).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BigPint software website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lindsayrutter.github.io/bigPint/&#34;&gt;https://lindsayrutter.github.io/bigPint/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Article explaining the BigPint methodology:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bmcbioinformatics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12859-019-2968-1&#34;&gt;https://bmcbioinformatics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12859-019-2968-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research article showcasing the BigPint software:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bmcgenomics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12864-019-5767-1&#34;&gt;https://bmcgenomics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12864-019-5767-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Article explaining the BigPint software:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1007912&#34;&gt;https://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1007912&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lindsay Rutter; Dianne Cook&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lindsayrutter/bigPint&#34;&gt;https://github.com/lindsayrutter/bigPint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PsychRNN: An Accessible and Flexible Python Package for Training Recurrent Neural Network Models on Cognitive Tasks</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/psychrnn_an_accessible_and_flexible_python_package_for_training_recurrent_neural_network_models_on_cognitive_tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/psychrnn_an_accessible_and_flexible_python_package_for_training_recurrent_neural_network_models_on_cognitive_tasks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PsychRNN is designed for neuroscientists and psychologists who are interested in RNNs as models of cognitive function in the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite growing interest in RNNs as models of brain function, this approach poses relatively high barriers to entry to researchers, due to the technical know-how required for specialized deep learning software (e.g. TensorFlow or PyTorch) to train artificial neural network models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We designed PsychRNN with accessibility and flexibility as important goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The frontend for users to define tasks and train RNNs uses only Python &amp;amp; NumPy, with no requirement for deep learning software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The backend, based on TensorFlow for model training, is readily extensible. This design allows for accessible high-level specification and parameterization of tasks and models, using only a few lines of Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modularity is central to PsychRNN&amp;rsquo;s design, to achieve flexibility in defining and parameterizing tasks and networks. This facilitates investigation of how task features (e.g. timing or input/output channels) shape the network solutions learned by the models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PsychRNN also provides support for implementation of neurobiologically motivated constraints on synaptic connectivity, such as: no autapses, structured connectivity (e.g. for multi-region RNNs), Dale&amp;rsquo;s principle (separate excitatory &amp;amp; inhibitory cells), and fixed nonplastic subset of synapses. Modularity enables implementation of curriculum learning, or task shaping. RNNs can be trained in closed-loop, with tasks progressively adjusted as behavioral performance improves. This is more similar to animal training, for investigation of how shaping impacts neural solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel B Ehrlich; Jasmine T Stone; David Brandfonbrener; Alexander Atanasov; John D Murray&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/murraylab/PsychRNN&#34;&gt;https://github.com/murraylab/PsychRNN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Jasmine Stone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INCF NeuroStars</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/incf_neurostars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/incf_neurostars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Neurostars is an open source question and answer site that serves the INCF network and the global neuroscience community as a forum for knowledge exchange between neuroscience researchers at all levels of expertise, software developers, and infrastructure providers. Access to Neurostars is free to the neuroscience community thanks to the generous support of our sponsors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neurostars is a forum for research questions, software, infrastructure, scientific societies, and virtual courses, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software developers and infrastructure providers in need of a mechanism in which to engage and provide support to user communities and those in need of a platform to integrate tutorials and discussion forums (via INCF TrainingSpace)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scientific societies in need of a forum for knowledge exchange and support between members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtual course organizers in need of an archivable Q &amp;amp; A forum to support learning in their courses where access can be restricted to registered participants with automated notifications and the ability to have multiple, linked subdiscussion groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individuals in need of sharing ideas, asking questions and finding answers, and helping others within neuroscience without any cost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INCF team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://neurostars.org&#34;&gt;https://neurostars.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-video&#34;&gt;Project Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=veVD1olyaW4&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=veVD1olyaW4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Malin Sandström&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INCF TrainingSpace</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/incf_trainingspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/incf_trainingspace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TrainingSpace is an online hub that aims to make neuroscience educational materials more accessible to the global neuroscience community developed by the Training and Education Committee composed of members from the INCF network, HBP, SfN, FENS, IBRO, IEEE, BD2K, and iNeuro Initiative. As a hub, TrainingSpace provides users with access to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multimedia educational content from courses, conference lectures, and laboratory exercises from some of the world’s leading neuroscience institutes and societies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Study tracks to facilitate self-guided study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tutorials on tools and open science resources for neuroscience research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Q&amp;amp;A forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A neuroscience encyclopedia that provides users with access to over 1.000.000 publicly available datasets as well as links to literature references and scientific abstracts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics currently included in TrainingSpace include: general neuroscience, clinical neuroscience, computational neuroscience, neuroinformatics, computer science, data science, and open science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All courses and conference lectures in TrainingSpace include a general description, topics covered, links to prerequisite courses if applicable, and links to software described in or required for the course, as well as links to the next lecture in the course or more advanced related courses. In addition to providing resources for students and researchers, TrainingSpace also provides resources for instructors, such laboratory exercises, open science services, and access to publicly available datasets and models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INCF team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://training.incf.org&#34;&gt;https://training.incf.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-video&#34;&gt;Project Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nHnW0z2qeQE&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nHnW0z2qeQE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Malin Sandström&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Brain</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/open_source_brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/open_source_brain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open Source Brain, a platform for sharing, viewing, analyzing, and simulating standardized models from different brain regions and species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Model structure and parameters can be automatically visualized and their dynamical properties explored through browser-based simulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infrastructure and tools for collaborative interaction, development, and testing are also provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Source Brain contributors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opensourcebrain.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.opensourcebrain.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Ankur Sinha (@ OSB/University College London)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MorphoPy: A python package for feature extraction of neural morphologies</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/morphopy_a_python_package_for_feature_extraction_of_neural_morphologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/morphopy_a_python_package_for_feature_extraction_of_neural_morphologies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MorphoPy is an open software package written in Python3 that allows for visualization and processing of morphological reconstructions of neural data. It has been created to facilitate the translation from morphology graphs into descriptive features like density maps, morphometric statistics, and persistence diagrams for down-stream exploration and statistical analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sophie Laturnus; Adam von Daranyi; Ziwei Huang; Philipp Berens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/berenslab/MorphoPy&#34;&gt;https://github.com/berenslab/MorphoPy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Sophie Laturnus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIPY</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/dipy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/dipy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DIPY is the paragon 3D/4D+ imaging library in Python. Contains generic methods for spatial normalization, signal processing, machine learning, statistical analysis and visualization of medical images. Additionally, it contains specialized methods for computational anatomy including diffusion, perfusion and structural imaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dipy/dipy/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt;https://github.com/dipy/dipy/graphs/contributors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dipy.org&#34;&gt;https://dipy.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-video&#34;&gt;Project Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnEuCRDGFOR5cfEo0nD3pw&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnEuCRDGFOR5cfEo0nD3pw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NeuroFedora</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/neurofedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/neurofedora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NeuroFedora is an initiative to provide a ready to use Fedora Linux based Free/Open source software platform for neuroscience. We believe that similar to Free software, science should be free for all to use, share, modify, and study. The use of Free software also aids reproducibility, data sharing, and collaboration in the research community. By making the tools used in the scientific process easier to use, NeuroFedora aims to take a step to enable this ideal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NeuroFedora volunteers @ the Fedora project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://neuro.fedoraproject.org&#34;&gt;https://neuro.fedoraproject.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Ankur Sinha (NeuroFedora SIG member)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataJoint</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/datajoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/datajoint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DataJoint is an open-source library for managing and sharing scientific data pipelines in Python and Matlab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DataJoint allows creating and sharing computational data pipelines, which are defined as databases and analysis code for executing steps of activities for data collection and analysis. For example, many neuroscience studies are organized around DataJoint pipelines that start with basic information about the experiment, then ingest acquired data, and then perform processing, analysis, and visualization of results. The entire pipeline is diagrammed as a graph where each node is a table in the database with a corresponding class in the programming language; together they define the data structure and computations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DataJoint key features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;access to shared data pipelines in a relational database (MySQL-compatible) from Python, Matlab, or both.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;data integrity and consistency based founded on the relational data model and transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an intuitive data definition language for pipeline design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a diagramming notation to visualize data structure and dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a serialization framework: storing large numerical arrays and other scientific data in a language-independent way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a flexible query language to retrieve precise cross-sections of data in a desired format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;automated  execution of computational jobs, with built-in job management for distributed computing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;managed storage of large data objects outside the database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dimitri Yatsenko; Edgar Walker; Fabian Sinz; Christopher Turner; Raphael Guzman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://datajoint.io&#34;&gt;https://datajoint.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Dimitri Yatsenko&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heuristic Spike Sorting Tuner (HSST), a framework to determine optimal parameter selection for a generic spike sorting algorithm</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/heuristic_spike_sorting_tuner_hsst_a_framework_to_determine_optimal_parameter_selection_for_a_generic_spike_sorting_algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/heuristic_spike_sorting_tuner_hsst_a_framework_to_determine_optimal_parameter_selection_for_a_generic_spike_sorting_algorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Extracellular microelectrodes frequently record neural activity from more than one neuron in the vicinity of the electrode. The process of labeling each recorded spike waveform with the identity of its source neuron is called spike sorting and is often approached from an abstracted statistical perspective. However, these approaches do not consider neurophysiological realities and may ignore important features that could improve the accuracy of these methods. Further, standard algorithms typically require selection of at least one free parameter, which can have significant effects on the quality of the output. We describe a Heuristic Spike Sorting Tuner (HSST) that determines the optimal choice of the free parameters for a given spike sorting algorithm based on the neurophysiological qualification of unit isolation and signal discrimination. A set of heuristic metrics are used to score the output of a spike sorting algorithm over a range of free parameters resulting in optimal sorting quality. We demonstrate that these metrics can be used to tune parameters in several spike sorting algorithms. The HSST algorithm shows robustness to variations in signal to noise ratio, number and relative size of units per channel. Moreover, the HSST algorithm is computationally efficient, operates unsupervised, and is parallelizable for batch processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David A. Bjanes; Lee B. Fisher; Robert A. Gaunt; Douglas J. Weber&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/davidbjanes/hsst&#34;&gt;https://github.com/davidbjanes/hsst&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
David Bjanes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BossDB</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/bossdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/bossdb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BossDB is a volumetric database that lives in the AWS cloud. Hundreds of terabytes of electron microscopy, light microscopy, and x-ray tomography data are available for free download and study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a project you want to share with the world for free? Get in touch!
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/thebossdb&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/thebossdb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JHU|APL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bossdb.org/&#34;&gt;https://bossdb.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Jordan Matelsky&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suite2P</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/suite2p/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/suite2p/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Suite2P is a very modular imaging processing pipeline written in Python which allows you to perform registration of raw data movies, automatic cell detection, extraction of calcium traces and infers spike times. It is a very fast and accurate tool and can work on standard workstations. It also includes a visualization graphical user interface (GUI) that facilitates analysis and manual curation of the cell detection algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carsen Stringer and Marius Pachitariu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mouseland.github.io/suite2p/_build/html/index.html&#34;&gt;https://mouseland.github.io/suite2p/_build/html/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Miguel Fernandes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
