<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Optogenetics | Open Neuroscience</title>
    <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/categories/optogenetics/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://open-neuroscience.com/en/categories/optogenetics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Optogenetics</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC BY SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://open-neuroscience.com/images/icon_hu98f7bdece981985d79e430785ac9bc37_26395_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Optogenetics</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/categories/optogenetics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>PiVR</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/pivr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/pivr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PiVR is a system that allows experimenters to immerse small animals into virtual realities. The system tracks the position of the animal and presents light stimulation according to predefined rules, thus creating a virtual landscape in which the animal can behave. By using optogenetics, we have used PiVR to present fruit fly larvae with virtual olfactory realities, adult fruit flies with a virtual gustatory reality and zebrafish larvae with a virtual light gradient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PiVR operates at high temporal resolution (70Hz) with low latencies (&amp;lt;30 milliseconds) while being affordable (&amp;lt;US$500) and easy to build (&amp;lt;6 hours). Through extensive documentation (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.PiVR.org&#34;&gt;www.PiVR.org&lt;/a&gt;), this tool was designed to be accessible to a wide public, from high school students to professional researchers studying systems neuroscience in academia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project is open source (BSD-3) and the documented code written in the freely available programming language Python. We hope that PiVR will be adapted by advanced users for their particular needs, for example to create closed-loop experiments involving other sensory modalities (e.g., sound/vibration) through the use of PWM controllable devices. We envision PiVR to be used as the central module when creating virtual realities for a variety of sensory modalities. This ‘PiVR module’ takes care of detecting the animal and presenting the appropriate PWM signal that is then picked up by the PWM controllable device installed by the user, for example to produce a sound whenever an animal enters a pre-defined region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, PiVR is a powerful and affordable experimental platform allowing experimenters to create a wide array of virtual reality experiments. Our hope is that PiVR will be adapted by several labs to democratize closed-loop experiments and, by standardizing image quality and the animal detection algorithm, increase reproducibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Tadres; Matthieu Louis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.PiVR.org&#34;&gt;http://www.PiVR.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-video&#34;&gt;Project Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w5tIG6B6FWo&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w5tIG6B6FWo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
David Tadres&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LED Zappelin&#39;</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/led_zappelin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/led_zappelin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two-photon (2P) microscopy is a cornerstone technique in neuroscience research. However, combining 2P imaging with spectrally arbitrary light stimulation can be challenging due to crosstalk between stimulation light and fluorescence detection. To overcome this limitation, we present a simple and low-cost electronic solution based on an ESP32 microcontroller and a TLC5947 LED driver to rapidly time-interleave stimulation and detection epochs during scans. Implemented for less than $100, our design can independently drive up to 24 arbitrary spectrum LEDs to meet user requirements. We demonstrate the utility of our stimulator for colour vision experiments on the in vivo tetrachromatic zebrafish retina and for optogenetic circuit mapping in Drosophila.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maxime Zimmermann; Andre Maia Chagas; Philipp Bartel; Sinzi Pop, Lucia Pierto Godino; Tom Baden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/BadenLab/LED-Zappelin&#34;&gt;https://github.com/BadenLab/LED-Zappelin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Maxime Zimmermann&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addgene&#39;s AAV Data Hub</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/addgenes_aav_data_hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/addgenes_aav_data_hub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AAV are versatile tools used by neuroscientists for expression and manipulation of neurons. Many scientists have benefited from the high-quality, ready-to-use AAV prep service from Addgene, a nonprofit plasmid repository. However, it can be challenging to determine which AAV tool and techniques are best to use for an experiment. Scientists also may have questions about how much virus to inject or which serotype or promoter should be used to target the desired neuron or brain region. To help scientists answer these questions, Addgene launched an open platform called the AAV Data Hub (&lt;a href=&#34;https://datahub.addgene.org/aav/&#34;&gt;https://datahub.addgene.org/aav/&lt;/a&gt;) which allows researchers to easily share practical experimental details with the scientific community (AAV used, in vivo model used, injection site, injection volumes, etc.). The goal of this platform is to help scientists find the best AAV tool for their experiments by reviewing combined data from a broad range of research labs. The AAV Data Hub launched in late 2019 and over 100 experiments have since been contributed to this project. The dataset includes details and images from experiments conducted in six different species and several different expression sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Addgene&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://datahub.addgene.org/aav/&#34;&gt;https://datahub.addgene.org/aav/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-video&#34;&gt;Project Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZPKdr1RdtGI&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZPKdr1RdtGI&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Angela Abitua&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulse Pal</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/pulse-pal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/pulse-pal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulse Pal is an open and inexpensive (~$210) alternative to pulse generators used in neurophysiology research, and is most often used to create precisely timed light trains in optogenetics assays. Pulse Pal generates four channels of configurable square pulse trains ranging in voltage from +10 to -10V using a bipolar DAC. Two digital trigger channels can be used to start and stop playback. APIs are available in C++, Python and MATLAB, and the hardware designs and firmware are fully open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to check the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fneng.2014.00043/abstract&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; about it and their 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/pulsepalwiki/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;wiki page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
