<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Analysis, Tutorials &amp; learning portals | Open Neuroscience</title>
    <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/tags/data-analysis-tutorials-learning-portals/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://open-neuroscience.com/en/tags/data-analysis-tutorials-learning-portals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Data Analysis, Tutorials &amp; learning portals</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC BY SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://open-neuroscience.com/media/openneuroscience_logo_dark.svg</url>
      <title>Data Analysis, Tutorials &amp; learning portals</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/tags/data-analysis-tutorials-learning-portals/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>INCF TrainingSpace</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/incf_trainingspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/incf_trainingspace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TrainingSpace is an online hub that aims to make neuroscience educational materials more accessible to the global neuroscience community developed by the Training and Education Committee composed of members from the INCF network, HBP, SfN, FENS, IBRO, IEEE, BD2K, and iNeuro Initiative. As a hub, TrainingSpace provides users with access to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multimedia educational content from courses, conference lectures, and laboratory exercises from some of the world’s leading neuroscience institutes and societies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Study tracks to facilitate self-guided study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tutorials on tools and open science resources for neuroscience research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Q&amp;amp;A forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A neuroscience encyclopedia that provides users with access to over 1.000.000 publicly available datasets as well as links to literature references and scientific abstracts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics currently included in TrainingSpace include: general neuroscience, clinical neuroscience, computational neuroscience, neuroinformatics, computer science, data science, and open science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All courses and conference lectures in TrainingSpace include a general description, topics covered, links to prerequisite courses if applicable, and links to software described in or required for the course, as well as links to the next lecture in the course or more advanced related courses. In addition to providing resources for students and researchers, TrainingSpace also provides resources for instructors, such laboratory exercises, open science services, and access to publicly available datasets and models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INCF team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://training.incf.org&#34;&gt;https://training.incf.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-video&#34;&gt;Project Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nHnW0z2qeQE&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nHnW0z2qeQE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Malin Sandström&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
