<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simulations | Open Neuroscience</title>
    <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/categories/simulations/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://open-neuroscience.com/en/categories/simulations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Simulations</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC BY SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://open-neuroscience.com/media/openneuroscience_logo_dark.svg</url>
      <title>Simulations</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/categories/simulations/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>INCF TrainingSpace</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/incf_trainingspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/incf_trainingspace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TrainingSpace is an online hub that aims to make neuroscience educational materials more accessible to the global neuroscience community developed by the Training and Education Committee composed of members from the INCF network, HBP, SfN, FENS, IBRO, IEEE, BD2K, and iNeuro Initiative. As a hub, TrainingSpace provides users with access to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multimedia educational content from courses, conference lectures, and laboratory exercises from some of the world’s leading neuroscience institutes and societies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Study tracks to facilitate self-guided study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tutorials on tools and open science resources for neuroscience research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Q&amp;amp;A forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A neuroscience encyclopedia that provides users with access to over 1.000.000 publicly available datasets as well as links to literature references and scientific abstracts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics currently included in TrainingSpace include: general neuroscience, clinical neuroscience, computational neuroscience, neuroinformatics, computer science, data science, and open science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All courses and conference lectures in TrainingSpace include a general description, topics covered, links to prerequisite courses if applicable, and links to software described in or required for the course, as well as links to the next lecture in the course or more advanced related courses. In addition to providing resources for students and researchers, TrainingSpace also provides resources for instructors, such laboratory exercises, open science services, and access to publicly available datasets and models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INCF team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://training.incf.org&#34;&gt;https://training.incf.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-video&#34;&gt;Project Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nHnW0z2qeQE&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nHnW0z2qeQE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Malin Sandström&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Brain</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/open_source_brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/open_source_brain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open Source Brain, a platform for sharing, viewing, analyzing, and simulating standardized models from different brain regions and species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Model structure and parameters can be automatically visualized and their dynamical properties explored through browser-based simulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infrastructure and tools for collaborative interaction, development, and testing are also provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Source Brain contributors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opensourcebrain.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.opensourcebrain.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Ankur Sinha (@ OSB/University College London)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NeuroFedora</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/neurofedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/neurofedora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NeuroFedora is an initiative to provide a ready to use Fedora Linux based Free/Open source software platform for neuroscience. We believe that similar to Free software, science should be free for all to use, share, modify, and study. The use of Free software also aids reproducibility, data sharing, and collaboration in the research community. By making the tools used in the scientific process easier to use, NeuroFedora aims to take a step to enable this ideal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NeuroFedora volunteers @ the Fedora project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://neuro.fedoraproject.org&#34;&gt;https://neuro.fedoraproject.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Ankur Sinha (NeuroFedora SIG member)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LED Zappelin&#39;</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/led_zappelin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/led_zappelin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two-photon (2P) microscopy is a cornerstone technique in neuroscience research. However, combining 2P imaging with spectrally arbitrary light stimulation can be challenging due to crosstalk between stimulation light and fluorescence detection. To overcome this limitation, we present a simple and low-cost electronic solution based on an ESP32 microcontroller and a TLC5947 LED driver to rapidly time-interleave stimulation and detection epochs during scans. Implemented for less than $100, our design can independently drive up to 24 arbitrary spectrum LEDs to meet user requirements. We demonstrate the utility of our stimulator for colour vision experiments on the in vivo tetrachromatic zebrafish retina and for optogenetic circuit mapping in Drosophila.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maxime Zimmermann; Andre Maia Chagas; Philipp Bartel; Sinzi Pop, Lucia Pierto Godino; Tom Baden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/BadenLab/LED-Zappelin&#34;&gt;https://github.com/BadenLab/LED-Zappelin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Maxime Zimmermann&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
