<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Database | Open Neuroscience</title>
    <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/tags/database/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://open-neuroscience.com/en/tags/database/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Database</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC BY SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://open-neuroscience.com/images/icon_hu98f7bdece981985d79e430785ac9bc37_26395_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Database</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/tags/database/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome RNAi</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/genome-rnai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/genome-rnai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.genomernai.org/Index&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GenomeRNAi  &lt;/a&gt; is a database containing phenotypes from RNA interference (RNAi) screens in Drosophila and Homo sapiens. In addition, the database provides an updated resource of RNAi reagents and their predicted quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neuromorpho</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/neuromorpho/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/neuromorpho/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://neuromorpho.org/index.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NeuroMorpho.Org&lt;/a&gt; is a centrally curated inventory of &lt;strong&gt;digitally reconstructed neurons&lt;/strong&gt; associated with peer-reviewed publications. It contains contributions from over 100 laboratories worldwide and is continuously updated as new morphological reconstructions are collected, published, and shared. (taken from neuromorpho.org)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addgene</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/addgene/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/addgene/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.addgene.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Addgene&lt;/a&gt; is a non-profit company that makes the share of plasmids easier by making a plasmid database and linking them to the papers where they were described. In this way they take on the job of maintaining plasmids and shipping them to requesting scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allen Brain Map</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/allen-brain-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/allen-brain-map/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brain-map.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Brain Map&lt;/a&gt; is one of the initiatives of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alleninstitute.org/about/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Allen Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a data portal that encompasses different projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the Allen Institute has created a set of large-scale programs to understand the fundamentals of the cortex. We will be focusing our understanding through simultaneous study of the brain&amp;rsquo;s  components, computation and cognition.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the Allen Institute has produced a collection of open science resources that give users a powerful way to explore gene expression data, neural connections, single cell characterization and neuroanatomy. All of our resources are openly accessible via the Allen Brain Atlas data portal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data repositories</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/data-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/data-repositories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In here are some examples of tools that can be used to share/store data collected. Published a paper and think that people would benefit from looking at the raw data? Want to make that data that has been stored for years useful? Here you’ll find some options on how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://figshare.com/about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FigShare&lt;/a&gt;: Free repository that allows storage of any sort of files (data, code, schematics) and gives each of them a digital object identifier (also keeping track to any changes made), which makes them citable. Also the website has tools to share the data.&lt;figure id=&#34;attachment_1270&#34; style=&#34;width: 167px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/df/Figshare_logo.svg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://datadryad.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dryad&lt;/a&gt;: Repository for data, works in a similar way to Figshare, but Dryad also has a data submission system integrated with a (growing) number of journals, so that paper submissions are synchronized with the data sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NeuroElectro</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/neuroelectro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/neuroelectro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://neuroelectro.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NeuroElectro&lt;/a&gt; wants to extract information about neuron types, morphology, electrophysiology properties from papers, using text mining algorithms and gathers them in a database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to facilitate the discovery of 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://neuroelectro.org/neuroelectro/neuron/clustering&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;neuron-to-neuron relationships&lt;/a&gt; and better understand the role of functional diversity across neuron types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;embed-youtube&#34; style=&#34;text-align:center; display: block;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open science framework</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/open-science-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/open-science-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://openscienceframework.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open science framework&lt;/a&gt; webpage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Open Science Framework (OSF) is part network of research materials, part version control system, and part collaboration software. The purpose of the software is to support the scientist’s workflow and help increase the alignment between scientific values and scientific practices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project offers cloud space for uploading of project outline, materials, workflow, individual contributions and their extent to a specific project. All of that with the option of having all data publicly or privately available. The idea is to allow a more transparent and innovative system where people can see what is being done in “real-time”, contribute and even take up on ideas from other people so that the wheel doesn’t have to be reinvented, the system also allows for proper citation, so that the “wheel inventors” won’t go uncredited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example of what can be done through the Open Science Framework, one can cite the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://openscienceframework.org/project/EZcUj/wiki/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Reproducibility Project&lt;/a&gt; which is a project that aims at checking the reproducibility of ~150 sample studies from cognitive and psychological sciences. Contributors are welcomed!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open source brain</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/open-source-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/open-source-brain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opensourcebrain.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;open source brain&lt;/a&gt; project is a database of computational models of neural systems.  From the website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Source Brain&lt;/strong&gt; is a resource for sharing and collaboratively developing  &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_neuroscience&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;computational models of neural systems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OSB will provide advanced facilities to analyse, visualise and transform models, and to connect researchers interested in models of specific neurons, brain regions and disease states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Visible Human project</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/the-visible-human-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/the-visible-human-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nlm.nih.gov/research/visible/visible_human.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Visible Human Project&lt;/a&gt; is a database of anatomical images (MR, CT and radiography) from male and female bodies. Information about the database is translated into a couple of different languages. Although an license needs to be signed and sent over to the NIH, the procedure seems to be straightforward and cost free.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
