<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Molecular biology | Open Neuroscience</title>
    <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/categories/molecular-biology/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://open-neuroscience.com/en/categories/molecular-biology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Molecular biology</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC BY SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://open-neuroscience.com/images/icon_hu98f7bdece981985d79e430785ac9bc37_26395_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/categories/molecular-biology/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>culture_shock</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/culture_shock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/culture_shock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Culture Shock is an open-source electroporator that was developed
through internet based collaboration, starting on the DIYbio Google
Group. It is an evolution on the traditional capacitive discharge
circuit topology, instead using pulsed induction to enable a
programmable waveform as well as reduce the size, weight, and cost of
the equipment. With all these benefits, we hope to reduce the burden
of laboratory consumables for DNA transformation and electrofusion
procedures, where chemical supplies are currently relied on. The added
benefit of programmability allows many cell types to be manipulated by
altering the voltage level, or even giving the voltage profile a
particular shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Griessen; Nathan McCorkle; Bryan Bishop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kanzure/culture_shock&#34;&gt;https://github.com/kanzure/culture_shock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Nathan McCorkle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poseidon</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/poseidon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/poseidon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Poseidon is an open-source syringe pump and microscope system. It uses 3D printed parts and common components that can be easily purchased. It can be used in microfluidics experiments or other applications. You can assemble it in a short-time for under $400. The system is modular and highly customizable. Examples of applications are: control the chemical environment of a bioreactor, purify proteins and precisely add reagents to chemical reactions over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pachter Lab&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pachterlab.github.io/poseidon&#34;&gt;https://pachterlab.github.io/poseidon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Miguel Fernandes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenTrons</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/opentrons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/opentrons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, biologists spend too much time pipetting by hand. We think biologists should have robots to do pipetting for them. People doing science should be free of tedious benchwork and repetitive stress injuries. They should be able to spend their time designing experiments and analyzing data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why we started Opentrons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We make robots for biologists. Our mission is to provide the scientific community with a common platform to easily share protocols and reproduce each other&amp;rsquo;s results. Our robots automate experiments that would otherwise be done by hand, allowing our community to spend more time pursuing answers to some of the 21st century’s most important questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opentrons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opentrons.com/about&#34;&gt;https://opentrons.com/about&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-video&#34;&gt;Project Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCvMRmXIxnHs3AutkVhuqaQg&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCvMRmXIxnHs3AutkVhuqaQg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Matias Andina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample Rotator Mixer and Shaker</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/sample_rotator_mixer_and_shaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/en/post/sample_rotator_mixer_and_shaker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An open-source 3-D printable laboratory sample rotator mixer is developed here in two variants that allow users to opt for the level of functionality, cost saving and associated complexity needed in their laboratories. First, a laboratory sample rotator is designed and demonstrated that can be used for tumbling as well as gentle mixing of samples in a variety of tube sizes by mixing them horizontally, vertically, or any position in between. Changing the mixing angle is fast and convenient and requires no tools. This device is battery powered and can be easily transported to operate in various locations in a lab including desktops, benches, clean hoods, chemical hoods, cold rooms, glove boxes, incubators or biological hoods. Second, an on-board Arduino-based microcontroller is incorporated that adds the functionality of a laboratory sample shaker. These devices can be customized both mechanically and functionally as the user can simply select the operation mode on the switch or alter the code to perform custom experiments. The open source laboratory sample rotator mixer can be built by non-specialists for under US$30 and adding shaking functionality can be done for under $20 more. Thus, these open source devices are technically superior to the proprietary commercial equipment available on the market while saving over 90% of the costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MOST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.appropedia.org/Open_Source_Laboratory_Sample_Rotator_Mixer_and_Shaker&#34;&gt;https://www.appropedia.org/Open_Source_Laboratory_Sample_Rotator_Mixer_and_Shaker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-video&#34;&gt;Project Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ta2ACV1oIjI&amp;amp;feature=emb_logo&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ta2ACV1oIjI&amp;amp;feature=emb_logo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Matias Andina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
