<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Electric stimulation | Open Neuroscience</title>
    <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/category/electric-stimulation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://open-neuroscience.com/category/electric-stimulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Electric stimulation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC BY SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://open-neuroscience.com/media/openneuroscience_logo_dark.svg</url>
      <title>Electric stimulation</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/category/electric-stimulation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurolib</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/neurolib/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/neurolib/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Easy whole-brain modeling for computational neuroscientists 👩🏿‍🔬💻🧠&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its essence, neurolib is a computational framework for simulating coupled neural mass models written in Python. It helps you to easily load structural brain scan data to construct brain networks where each node is a neural mass representing a single brain area. This network model can be used to simulate whole-brain dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;neurolib provides a simulation and optimization framework which allows you to easily implement your own neural mass model, simulate fMRI BOLD activity, analyse the results and fit your model to empirical data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With neurolib, our goal is to create a hackable framework for coders and focus on the simulation and optimization machinery. In this sense, neurolib is primarily a modern research tool and our main goal is to provide an accessible research framework. However, it is built with people in mind who are new to the field and just want to get going. We have made it as easy as possible to setup a simulation or to implement your own model and run your experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caglar Cakan; Nikola Jajcay&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/neurolib-dev/neurolib&#34;&gt;https://github.com/neurolib-dev/neurolib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Caglar Cakan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>culture_shock</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/culture_shock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/culture_shock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Culture Shock is an open-source electroporator that was developed
through internet based collaboration, starting on the DIYbio Google
Group. It is an evolution on the traditional capacitive discharge
circuit topology, instead using pulsed induction to enable a
programmable waveform as well as reduce the size, weight, and cost of
the equipment. With all these benefits, we hope to reduce the burden
of laboratory consumables for DNA transformation and electrofusion
procedures, where chemical supplies are currently relied on. The added
benefit of programmability allows many cell types to be manipulated by
altering the voltage level, or even giving the voltage profile a
particular shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Griessen; Nathan McCorkle; Bryan Bishop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kanzure/culture_shock&#34;&gt;https://github.com/kanzure/culture_shock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Nathan McCorkle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labmaker</title>
      <link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/labmaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/labmaker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LabMaker is a maker and assembly service for OPEN SCIENCE instruments. OPEN SCIENCE initiatives provide part lists or &amp;ldquo;Bill Of Materials&amp;rdquo; (BOM) for openly available scientific instruments. LabMaker bridges the gap between the BOM and the ready-to-use instrument for those not wanting to build by themselves. LabMaker is based in Berlin, Germany and ships worldwide. Berlin, as a city, is not only amongst the frontrunners for the title &amp;ldquo;start-up capital of Europe&amp;rdquo;, but also home to a large diversity of companies rooted in traditional precision manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-authors&#34;&gt;Project Author(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Labmaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-links&#34;&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.labmaker.org/&#34;&gt;https://www.labmaker.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated by
Matias Andina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
